Contact

Hanoi, Vietnam brother.rain.1024@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/vuanh-41254943 (LinkedIn) undertheseanlp.com (Personal)

Top Skills

Security

Technical Design

Natural Language Processing (NLP)

Languages

English (Professional Working)
Vietnamese (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Machine Learning

Introduction to Recommender Systems

Improving Deep Neural Networks: Hyperparameter tuning, Regularization and Optimization

Neural Networks and Deep Learning

Structuring Machine Learning Projects

Honors-Awards

Second Rank, VLSP Competition Award

Vu Anh

Lead Al Engineer - NLP

Vietnam

Summary

- Building Generative AI solutions
- Built Underthesea the popular open-source Vietnamese NLP toolkit (1500+ github stars)

My work centers on creating practical AI applications that bridge cutting-edge research with real-world business value - from custom LLM implementations to AI-powered automation systems that enhance productivity and unlock new possibilities for enterprise innovation.

Specialties:

- Al: Generative Al, Chatbot Development, Deep Learning
- Big Data
- Software Development

Email: anhv.ict91 [at] gmail [dot] com

Github: github.com/rain1024

Experience

MoMo (M_Service)
Lead Al Engineer - NLP
July 2021 - Present (4 years 1 month)

Ho Chi Minh City, Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

VNDIRECT Securities Corporation Technical Lead - Big Data & Al January 2021 - June 2021 (6 months)

Hanoi, Hanoi, Vietnam

OSP GROUP

Engineering Manager - Big Data & Al

Page 1 of 2

February 2018 - December 2020 (2 years 11 months)

Hanoi, Hanoi, Vietnam

1LINK JSC

4 years

Technical Lead - Software Engineer March 2016 - January 2018 (1 year 11 months)

Hanoi, Hanoi, Vietnam

Senior Software Engineer February 2014 - February 2016 (2 years 1 month)

Hanoi, Hanoi, Vietnam

Bkav Corp.
Security Researcher
June 2011 - October 2012 (1 year 5 months)
Hanoi, Hanoi, Vietnam

Education

Hanoi University of Science and Technology Engineer's degree · (June 2014)